Personal Profile

I am a Full Stack Developer with a strong academic background and professional commercial experience assisting users and developers with technical product integration. I understand the product development lifecycle and am capable at all aspects of development from project planning to requirements gathering through to writing and testing code, creating documentation and supporting clients with integration.

Education

Udemy, Remote — UX, UI Research and Design and Web Development, Jul 2018 — May 2019

City University London, London — BSc (Hons) Criminology and Sociology, Sept 2013 — Aug 2018

Tower Hamlets College, London — A-Levels Psychology (C), Sociology (C), Media Studies (A) and Communication and Culture (B) , SEPT 2011 — AUG 2013

Tower Hamlets College, London — BTEC Level 3 Diploma Information and Technology Sept 2009 — Aug 2011

Highams Park School, London — 5 A^* - C Subjects Incl. English, Mathematics, Advanced Mathematics, and Science, Sept 2004 — Aug 2009

Experience

Full Stack Developer, le Wagon London, Nov 2019 — March 2020

My GitHub profile: https://github.com/iram-shehzadi Attended Le Wagon London (Batch 360).

iIntensive coding bootcamp learning HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript ES2015, SQL, git, GitHub, Heroku and Ruby on Rails. Designed, implemented and shipped to production a clone of AirBnB and a Rails prototype.

- Core concepts of object-oriented programming (OOP)
- Software structuring following design patterns like MVC
- 3rd party service integration using an API or scrape HTML data
- Relational database design and queries creation with SQL
- UI development following atomic design framework
- CSS library set-up using recent techniques like flex-box or CSS grid
- ES6 as a second programming language
- * Test Driven Development (TDD) to cover application's code with unit tests

Solutions Engineer, Buyapowa London, Sept 2019 — Oct 2019

- Reviewed and analysed current technologies used within the company and developed steps and processes to improve
- Documented and monitored requirements needed to institute proposed updates in relation to customer experience
- Worked alongside project management teams to successfully monitor progress and implementation of initiatives
- · Provided detailed specifications for proposed solutions including time and scope involved

Integration Analyst, Buyapowa London, May 2019 — Sept 2019

- Successfully managed the integration and testing process. Analysed and suggested improvements to product, which resulted in changes to product
- · Assisting clientele with technical queries using HTML, CSS, Ruby on Rails and Javascript
- Assisting developers with test practices after integration
- Managing support channels and providing support to live clients using Slack, Asana, Zoom and Zendesk

- Reviewing, analysing, and reporting on the effectiveness and efficiency of existing systems and developing strategies for improvement
- · Creating new and updating existing technical documents for both internal and external use
- Creating user journey flow charts

Developer, Freelance Remote, Aug 2017 — May 2019

Between 2017 and 2019 I worked on several freelance projects where I built and maintained web apps or websites for my clients. I worked to understand their business needs and aimed to deliver solutions that helped them achieve their goals.

Skills

Stack - HTML, SCSS, Ruby, JavaScript

Frameworks — Ruby on Rails, Bootstrap, familiar with React, Redux **Tools** — Node. js, SQL, PostgreSQL, Git, Github, Figma, Adobe XD, Sketch, Heroku, Netlify,